Preliminary Guide to the Douglas M. Knight Records, 1949 - 1970
Duke University. University Archives
- Subject Files, 1952-1969
  - Presidents' Meeting with Secretary of State re: Vietnam, 1967-1968 (Box 21)
  - President's New House [1508 Pinecrest Road], [2 folders] (Box 21)
  - President's Report to Faculty, 1964-1965 (Box 21)
  - President's Report to Trustees, 1963-1969, [17 folders] (Box 21)
  - President's Schedule, 1963-1968 (Box 21)
  - President's Speeches -- Index to ideas, 1963-1969 (Box 21)
  - Priority Problems [Physical Plant], 1964 (Box 21)
  - Provost Group, 1963-1969, [3 folders] (Box 21)
  - Provost's Report, 1966-1968 (Box 22)
  - Public Relations, 1967-1969 (Box 22)
  - Public Relations Advisory Committee [John Paul Lucas, Chairman], 1965-1968 (Box 22)
  - "Publish or Perish," 1967 (Box 22)
  - Questionnaires, 1964-1969 (Box 22)
  - Rauch, Henry E., 1965-1966, [2 folders] (Box 22)
  - Regional Cultural Assistance Program, 1969 (Box 22)
  - Regional Education Laboratory -- Mid-South, 1962-1965 (Box 22)
  - Registrar's Office, 1964-1969 (Box 22)
  - Research Triangle -- Textile Research Institute [George Norman, Burlington Industries], 1967 (Box 22)
  - Research Triangle Foundation, 1963-1969 (Box 22)
  - Research Triangle Institute, 1963-1969, [2 folders] (Box 22)
  - Research Triangle Institute (Box 22)
    - University Relations Group, 1965 (Box 22)
  - Retired Officers Program in Mathematics, 1966 (Box 22)
  - Retirement Residences, 1967-1968 (Box 22)
  - Rickards, Edward, 1964-1968 (Box 22)
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund [Nancy Hanks], 1964-1966 (Box 22)
  - Rockefeller Grant -- Duke-Emory-Tulane-Vanderbilt [Assistance to Disadvantaged Southern Students], 1963-1968 (Box 22)
  - Salzburg Seminar, 1963 (Box 22)
  - Schumann, Marguerite, 1963-1968 (Box 22)
  - Securities Seminar, 1968 (Box 22)
  - Security Division, 1968 (Box 22)
  - Seminars [Not Student], 1967-1969 (Box 22)
  - Slavic Studies [ACLS], 1964-1968 (Box 22)
  - Smith Island, 1964-1965 (Box 22)
  - Smithsonian Institution, 1964 (Box 22)
  - Society for Religion in Higher Education, 1963-1968 (Box 22)
  - Society for the Family of Man, 1968 (Box 22)
  - South Atlantic Quarterly, 1963-1968 (Box 22)
  - Southeastern American Studies Association, 1967-1968 (Box 22)
  - Southeastern Institute of Medieval & Renaissance Studies, 1965-1969 (Box 22)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools, 1963-1968, [2 folders] (Box 22)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools (Box 22)
    - Project Opportunity, 1964 (Box 22)
  - Southern Education Foundation -- Southern Fellowships Fund, 1966 (Box 22)
  - Southern Humanities Conference, 1964-1965 (Box 22)
  - Southern Regional Education Board, 1963-1969 (Box 23)
  - Southern Society -- New York, NY, 1965-1966 (Box 23)
  - Southern University Conference, 1963-1969 (Box 23)
  - Southside School, 1966 (Box 23)
  - Soviet-Chinese Conflict -- Symposium, Sept. 25-26, 1964 (Box 23)
  - Spaulding, Asa T., 1963-1969 (Box 23)
  - Speaker Ban Law -- UNC Commencement Speech, 1965 (Box 23)
  - Special Events -- Whitener, 1963-1964 (Box 23)
  - Spengler, Joseph, 1963-1969 (Box 23)
  - Sponsored Research Grants [Coordination of Projects], 1965-1968 (Box 23)
  - St. Andrews Presbyterian College -- Laurinburg, NC, 1964-1966 (Box 23)
  - State Support for Private Institutions, 1968 (Box 23)
  - Statistics -- General, 1962-1966 (Box 23)
  - Student (Box 23)
    - Controversial Speakers [Adam Clayton Powell; Stokely Carmichael], 1966-1969 (Box 23)
    - "Divina Commedia", 1967-1968 (Box 23)
    - "Ex Calibur", 1966-1968 (Box 23)
    - May Queen, 1967 (Box 23)
    - Payday [East Campus], 1963 (Box 23)
    - Sororities, 1967 (Box 23)
    - Speaker Ban Law, 1963-1965, [2 folders] (Box 23)
    - Speaker Controversy, 1966, [4 folders] (Box 23)
    - Speaker Letters [in Re: Controversial Speakers], 1966-1967 (Box 23)
    - Speakers [Letters and Answers], 1966 (Box 23)
    - Visiting Resident Scholar Program, 1968 (Box 23)
    - Voting Age Council, 1967 (Box 23)
  - Student Affairs [Symposium, The Real World, 1963-1965], 1966-1969, [2 folders] (Box 23)
  - Student Affairs -- In Loco Parentis, 1966 (Box 23)
  - Student Coffee House, 1966-1968 (Box 23)
  - Student Demonstrations [Clippings], 1967-1968 (Box 23)
  - Student Fees, 1967 (Box 23)
  - Student Government -- ASDU, 1967-1969 (Box 23)
  - Student Government Association (Box 23)
    - Men's, 1963-1967 (Box 23)
    - Women's [see also box 26], 1965-1966 (Box 23)
  - Student Health Advisory Committee, 1967 (Box 23)
  - Student Health Department, 1963-1968 (Box 23)
  - Student Petitions [see box 26] (Box 23)
  - Student Records, 1966-1967 (Box 23)
  - Student Rights (Box 24)
    - Berkeley, etc., 1965 (Box 24)
    - Colorado Court Decision, 1968 (Box 24)
    - Resource Material, 1967 (Box 24)
  - Student Rights and Activism, 1966-1968 (Box 24)
  - Student Rights and Freedoms, 1967 (Box 24)
  - Summer Intern Program, 1965 (Box 24)
  - Summer Programs (Box 24)
  - Summer Session, 1964-1966 (Box 24)
  - Superannuates, 1967-1968 (Box 24)
  - Superior Student, 1963-1967 (Box 24)
  - Symposium, [6 folders] (Box 24)
  - Taft Institute, 1964-1967 (Box 24)
  - Teachers Insurance & Annuity Association, 1963-1968 (Box 24)
  - Telephones, 1964-1965 (Box 24)
  - Texas Gulf Sulfur [Mining Operation], 1967 (Box 24)
  - Theological Education, The Fund for, 1964-1968, [2 folders] (Box 24)
  - Thomas, Brinkley [International Studies], 1964-1965 (Box 24)
  - Thorne, Sam T., Jr. -- Prospect Evaluation Committee, 1965-1968 (Box 24)
  - Traffic Commission [Parking], 1963-1969 (Box 24)
  - Triangle Resident Theater Company, 1964-1965 (Box 24)
  - Triangle Universities Computation Center, 1966-1969, [2 folders] (Box 24)
  - Trinity College, 1963-1969, [2 folders] (Box 24)
  - Trustees (Box 24)
    - Allen, George V. [Development Committee], 1965-1969 (Box 24)
    - Bowles, Charles, 1963-1968 (Box 24)
    - Budget and Audit Committee, 1966 (Box 24)
    - Campaign Operations Committee [Clifford Perry], 1965-1968 (Box 24)
    - Cocke, Norman [Lake James], 1964-1968 (Box 24)
    - Confidential "Special Files", [5 folders] (Box 24)
    - Correspondence (Box 25)
      - A-N, 1963-1970 (Box 25)
      - O-Z, 1963-1969 (Box 25)
      - General, n.d. (Box 25)
      - re: meeting of 10/63 (Box 25)
      - [Selected], 1964-1965 (Box 25)
    - Dinners, 1966-1968 (Box 25)
    - Founders' Day Dinner, 1968 (Box 25)
    - Graduate School of Business Administration, 1965-1969 (Box 25)
    - Honors, 1966 (Box 25)
    - Key Gifts Committee [Chairman B. Wade Jr.], 1967-1969 (Box 25)
    - Letter to Trustees Concerning 12/67 Meeting (Box 25)
    - Major Gifts Committee [Edwin L. Jones], 1965-1966 (Box 25)
    - Prospective Trustees, 1962-1968 (Box 25)
    - Rauch, Henry E., 1965-1969 (Box 25)
    - Special Gifts Committee, 1965-1967 (Box 25)
    - Student-Faculty Administration Committee Statement and Ltr. to Exec. Comm., 1967-1968 (Box 25)
    - Tisdale, Wright, 1963-1966 (Box 25)
    - Towe, Kenneth C., 1963-1967 (Box 25)
    - University Committee, 1965-1969 (Box 25)
  - Tuition, 1967 (Box 25)
  - United Fund [Segregated Facilities], 1964-1969 (Box 25)
  - United Nations, 1965-1969 (Box 25)
  - United States (Box 25)
    - Defense Department, 1963-1964 (Box 25)
    - Health, Education and Welfare Dept., 1963-1965 (Box 25)
  - Universities Research Association, 1964-1968, [3 folders] (Box 25)
  - University Car, 1966-1967 (Box 25)
  - University Governance, 1969 (Box 25)
  - University House, 1964-1967 (Box 25)
  - Urban Coalition, 1968-1969 (Box 25)
  - Veterans Administration Hospital [VINOCUR], 1965-1967 (Box 25)
  - Visitors, 1963-1967 (Box 25)
  - Watauga Club, 1965-1969 (Box 25)
  - Weiss, Paul [Rockefeller University], 1964-1967 (Box 25)
  - Werber, William M. (Box 25)
    - 1965-1967 (Box 25)
    - 1967-1969 (Box 26)
  - Woman's College (Box 26)
    - Experimental Off-Board Group, 1968 (Box 26)
    - Facilities, Safety, Renovations, etc., 1964-1968 (Box 26)
    - General, 1965-1969 (Box 26)
    - Long-Range Planning, 1963-1968 (Box 26)
    - Policies, 1963-1968 (Box 26)
    - Proposed Changes in Regulations, 1967 (Box 26)
    - Rules for Social Behavior, 1966-1969 (Box 26)
  - Woodhall, Barnes, 1963-1965; 1969, [2 folders] (Box 26)
  - YMCA-YWCA, 1968 (Box 26)
  - Woman's Student Government Association -- continued from box 23 (Box 26)
  - Student Petitions [legal-sized], 1965 (Box 26)
  - Budget Planning, 1968-1969 (Box 27)
  - Campus Club, 1963-1967 (Box 27)
  - Catalogue and Calendar, 1966-1969 (Box 27)
  - Carnegie Corporation, 1965-1969 (Box 27)
  - Center for Research on Problems of Aging, 1964-1969 (Box 27)
  - Center for Research in Science and Mathematics, 1964-1968 (Box 27)
  - Center for the Study of Higher Education, 1964-1965 (Box 27)
  - Chanticleer, 1967-1968 (Box 27)
  - Chapel -- Miscellaneous, 1967-1969 (Box 27)
  - Chapel Organ, 1966-1968 (Box 27)
  - Center for Southern Studies, 1964-1969 (Box 27)
  - Chaplain, 1963-1969 (Box 27)
  - Chronicle, 1968-1969 (Box 27)
  - Cleland, James T., Dean of the Chapel, 1963-1969 (Box 27)
  - Commonwealth Studies, 1964-1969 (Box 27)
  - DeLapp, Sim A., 1967-1968 (Box 27)
  - Department (Box 27)
    - Art, 1960-1969 (Box 27)
    - Biochemistry, 1966-1969 (Box 27)
    - Botany, 1962-1969 (Box 27)
    - Business Administration, 1967 (Box 27)
    - Chemistry, 1960-1967 (Box 27)
    - Classical Studies [Medieval and Renaissance Studies], 1962-1969 (Box 27)
    - Office of Computer Sciences, 1967 (Box 27)
    - Economics, 1960-1968, [2 folders] (Box 27)
    - Education, 1965-1969 (Box 27)
    - Electrical Engineering, 1967 (Box 27)
    - English, 1960-1969 (Box 27)
    - Forestry (Box 27)
      - 1952 (Box 27)
      - 1963-1969 (Box 27)
    - Geology, 1961-1968 (Box 27)
    - German, 1960-1967 (Box 27)
    - History, 1960-1969 (Box 27)
    - Law School, 1968-1969 (Box 27)
    - Mathematics, 1963-1969 (Box 27)
    - Music, 1962-1969 (Box 28)
    - Philosophy, 1962-1969 (Box 28)
    - Physical Education, 1959-1969 (Box 28)
    - Physical Therapy, 1961-1968 (Box 28)
    - Physics, 1961-1968 (Box 28)
    - Political Science, 1961-1968 (Box 28)
    - Psychiatry, 1960-1964 (Box 28)
    - Psychology, 1960-1969 (Box 28)
    - Religion, 1964-1969 (Box 28)
    - Romance Languages, 1962-1969 (Box 28)
    - Slavic Languages and Literatures (formerly Russian), 1963-1968 (Box 28)
    - Sociology, 1961-1969 (Box 28)
    - Zoology, 1960-1969 (Box 28)
  - Departmental Chairmen and Officers, 1963-1969 (Box 28)
  - DeVyver, Frank T., 1952, 1963-1969, [2 folders] (Box 28)
  - Duke Endowment (Box 28)
    - Committee on Educational Institutions (Paul H. Clyde), 1963-1968 (Box 28)
    - Perkins, T.L., 1965-1969 (Box 28)
    - Rural Church Program, 1959-1966 (Box 28)
  - Duke--Gothic Bookshop (Jeremy North) [Society of Book Collectors and Book Lovers of Duke University], 1963-1969 (Box 28)
  - Duke, James B., Fellowships, 1957-1966 (Box 28)
  - Duke University Council on Research, 1960-1968 (Box 28)
  - Duke University Marshal, 1964-1967 (Box 28)
  - Duke University Press, 1963-1969 (Box 28)
  - Duke University Stores, 1965-1966 (Box 28)
  - Dukes, Charles A. [Johnston Fund, Marse Jack Bell, Alyse Smith Cooper Fund], 1963-1966 (Box 28)
  - Engineering School, 1965-1969, [3 folders] (Box 28)
  - Engineering (Box 28)
    - Biomedical, 1966-1969 (Box 28)
    - Monorail, 1965 (Box 28)
    - Proposals, Reports, 1963-1969, [2 folders] (Box 29)
  - Enrollment Statistics (Box 29)
    - 1962-1966 (Box 29)
    - [Enrollment and Housing], 1967-1968 (Box 29)
  - Executive Health Examination Program, 1965-1967 (Box 29)
  - Faculty (Box 29)
    - Action and Communications, 1960-1969 (Box 29)
    - Gifts, 1964-1969 (Box 29)
    - Continuation Plan, 1968 (Box 29)
    - Lists Department Chairmen, 1959-1964 (Box 29)
    - Meetings, 1960-1968 (Box 29)
    - Retired, 1963-1969 (Box 29)
    - Salaries, 1964-1969, [4 folders] (Box 29)
  - Goodwin, Craufurd D., 1963-1969 (Box 29)
  - Graduate School (Box 29)
    - Associate Deans, 1966 (Box 29)
    - [The Draft], 1968 (Box 29)
  - Griffith, William J., 1965-1969 (Box 29)
  - Guilford College [President Grimsley Hobbs], 1965-1969 (Box 29)
  - Hanks, Nancy, 1965-1969 (Box 29)
  - Heyn, A.N.J., [1966?] (Box 29)
  - Hill, George Watts, 1963-1969 (Box 29)
  - Hobbs, Provost Marcus, 1963-1969, [2 folders] (Box 29)
  - Lewis, Harold W., 1965-1969 (Box 29)
  - Library -- Angier Biddle Duke Papers, 1965-1968 (Box 29)
  - Low Income Housing Development Corp. of North Carolina, 1968 (Box 29)
  - Methodist Church, 1966-1969 (Box 29)
  - National Advisory Commission on Libraries, Final Copy, July 2, 1968 (Box 29)
  - President's Discretionary Fund, 1969 (Box 29)
  - President's Office, 1964 (Box 29)
  - Security Survey, 1968-1969 (Box 29)
  - UNC-Duke Proposal to Strengthening Negro Education [African American], 1963-1965 (Box 29)
  - U.S. Office of Education -- Dept. of Health, Education and Welfare, 1965-1969 (Box 29)
  - Yale University's Stand on Financial Aid to Disruptive Students, 1969 (Box 29)
- Development Files, 1949-1970 (Box 29)
  Alphabetically arranged by the name of the foundation, corporation, or individual.
  Comprised of files primarily related to the Fifth Decade Campaign, the Development Files series is a group of working files that were used by the President's Office in ongoing institutional advancement efforts. The files contain memoranda, letters to and from Knight, and documents defining the terms of the gifts. Some files are useful for ascertaining specific information on gifts and grants.
  Duke University's efforts to attract underprivileged and black students is, in part, documented in records that relate to the Rockefeller Foundation. Development efforts in international studies are demonstrated through grant proposals and reports to the Ford Foundation. Edwin L. Jones, the R.J. Reynolds Tobacco Company, and the Hanes family are among the donors and potential donors represented in the records.
  Also of significance are statistics on scholarships, particularly the ratio of athletic scholarships to non-athletic scholarships. The file on the Lilly Research Program in Christianity and Politics contains letters from Professor Waldo Beach and the black theologian, Deotis Roberts, which focus upon the issue of Roberts's enrollment in a Lilly seminar during the late 1950s, when the campus was segregated.
  - Adams, Martha Lipscomb Scholarship Fund, 1964-1965 (Box 30)
  - The Alcoa Foundation (see also Hunt, Alfred M.), 1961-1969 (Box 30)
  - Allen, George Garland, 1955-1965 (Box 30)
  - Allen, George V., 1965-1969 (Box 30)
  - The American Tobacco Company, 1966-1967 (Box 30)
  - Babcock, Charles and Besty, 1966-1969 (Box 30)
  - Babcock, Mary Reynolds Foundation, 1962-1969 (Box 30)
  - Bailey, Louis William Fund, 1958-1970 (Box 30)
  - Baker, Virginia Flowers Professorship of Orthopedic Surgery Fund, 1964-1969 (Box 30)
  - Bethlehem Steel Corporation, 1957-1969 (Box 30)
  - Biddle, Mary Duke, Foundation, 1963-1969 (Box 30)
  - Booker, Warren H. and Anne Leaming Scholarship Fund, 1964-1965 (Box 30)
  - Bost, Thomas C. Scholarship Fund, 1966-1969 (Box 30)
  - Brinkley, Dean, Scholarship Fund, 1963 (Box 30)
  - Brinkley, Roberta Florence, International Scholarship Fund, 1965 (Box 30)
  - Burlington Industries, 1956-1958 (Box 30)
  - Cannon Foundation, 1966-1969 (Box 30)
  - Carter, F. Bayard, Chair of Obstetrics and Gynecology, 1964-1967 (Box 30)
  - Centenary Church [Building program, Duke Divinity School], 1964 (Box 30)
  - Chemstrand, 1958-1964 (Box 30)
  - The Cleland Scholarship, 1963-1965 (Box 30)
  - The Commonwealth Fund, 1958, 1962 (Box 30)
  - Cranmer, Carol Jean Memorial Scholarship, 1966-1969 (Box 30)
  - Davis, Arthur Vining Foundation, 1967-1970 (Box 30)
  - Davis, W. R. [Melba Jean Davis Greenlee, Daughter], 1963-1964 (Box 30)
  - Dreyfus Foundation, 1965-1969 (Box 30)
  - Duke, Angier B. Memorial Scholarships, 1952-1969 (Box 30)
  - Duke Power Company, 1966-1967 (Box 30)
  - Eastman Kodak Company, 1956-1967 (Box 30)
  - E. I. DuPont DeNemours and Company, 1952-1969 (Box 30)
  - Esso Education Foundation, 1965-1969 (Box 30)
  - Esso Foundation -- S.P.U.R. Project [Support for Promoting Utilization of Resources], 1965-1969 (Box 30)
  - Ford Foundation Grant, 1966-1969 (Box 30)
  - Ford Foundation (Box 30)
    - Cooperative Program in International Studies Proposal, 1966-1967 (Box 30)
    - Socio-economic Studies of Aging, 1960-1965 (Box 30)
    - Program of Training and Research in International Affairs, 1963-1970, [2 folders] (Box 30)
  - Ford Motor Company, 1954-1969 (Box 30)
  - Furniture Foundation, 1966-1967 (Box 30)
  - The General Electric Company, 1955-1969 (Box 30)
  - General Motors Corporation, 1959-1969 (Box 30)
  - Gibbons, J. P. [Chair in Psychiatry], 1961-1967 (Box 30)
  - Governmental Relations Advisory Committee, 1965 (Box 30)
  - Gulf Oil Corporation Foundation, 1959-1967 (Box 30)
  - Hanes Family, 1966-1969 (Box 31)
  - Hanes, Fred M. -- Bequest and Scholarship, 1946, 1966-1967 (Box 31)
  - Hercules Incorporated -- Werner Brown, 1966-1968 (Box 31)
  - Hunt, Alfred M. (see also Alcoa Foundation), 1967-1969 (Box 31)
  - I.B.M. (International Business Machines Corporation), 1959-1969 (Box 31)
  - Inman, Walker P. -- Memorial Gift, 1956-1958 (Box 31)
  - Jones, Edwin L., 1967-1969 (Box 31)
  - Jones, J. A. [Chair of Engineering], 1966-1970 (Box 31)
  - Jordan Family, 1966-1968 (Box 31)
  - Kearns, Gurney Harris Foundation, 1954-1969 (Box 31)
  - Kerner, Lewis Clarence, 1959 (Box 31)
  - The Lane Company, Incorporated, 1960-1969 (Box 31)
  - Laufer, Charles A. Scholarship Fund, 1952 (Box 31)
  - Lee, Lawrence F. Jr. -- Airplane-Lockheed Lodestar, 1968-1969 (Box 31)
  - Lee, W. S. Scholarship Fund, 1957 (Box 31)
  - Liggett and Myers Tobacco Co., 1966-1968 (Box 31)
  - Lilly Endowment, Incorporated [Lilly Endowment Research Program in Christianity and Politics], 1957-1965 (Box 31)
  - Markle, John and Mary R. Foundation, 1964-1967 (Box 31)
  - Marshall Scholarships, 1954-1965 (Box 31)
  - Medical School Gifts -- Eye Center, 1966-1969 (Box 31)
  - Mellon, Richard King Charitable Trusts, 1963-1969 (Box 31)
  - Merck Company Foundation [Loan Fund], 1959-1969 (Box 31)
  - Merrit Memorial Fund, 1957-1960 (Box 31)
  - Merrill-Renzulli Foundation, 1961 (Box 31)
  - Miscellaneous Foundations, Corporations, Gifts, Grants, 1966-1969, [2 folders] (Box 31)
  - Morehead Foundation Proposal, 1967 (Box 31)
  - Morehead Scholarships, 1951-1962 (Box 31)
  - Muse, William H. Scholarship Fund, 1963 (Box 31)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1964-1969 (Box 31)
  - National Methodist Scholarships, 1955-1963 (Box 31)
  - Norman, George E. Jr. Scholarship Fund, 1963-1964 (Box 31)
  - North Carolina Section -- American Water Works Association and N.C. Water Pollution Control Association, 1963 (Box 31)
  - Price, Martha Garner Research Fellowship, 1960-1965 (Box 31)
  - Proctor and Gamble Company, 1955-1969 (Box 31)
  - Proctor, Henry Simpson Loan Fund, 1952-1957 (Box 31)
  - Reynolds, Anne Cannon (Forsyth)/Z. Smith Reynolds Foundation, 1967-1966 (Box 31)
  - Reynolds, R. J. Tobacco Company, 1960-1968 (Box 31)
  - Reynolds, W. N. Loan Fund, 1949-1966 (Box 31)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1957-1970 (Box 31)
  - Ruffin, Julian M. Research Fund, 1965 (Box 31)
  - Scholarships -- Financial Aid -- Miscellaneous, 1952-1965 (Box 31)
  - Sears, Roebuck and Company, 1960-1968 (Box 31)
  - Shell Companies Foundation, 1958-1969 (Box 31)
  - Sidbury Chair in Pediatrics, 1964-1965 (Box 31)
  - Sloan, Alfred P. Foundation, 1955-1968 (Box 31)
  - Snow, Dr. and Mr. W. Brewster Fund, 1957-1959 (Box 31)
  - Southern Pacific Foundation -- Southern Pacific Company, 1965-1969 (Box 31)
  - Standard Oil Company (American Oil Foundation and Pan American Petroleum Foundation), 1960-1965 (Box 31)
  - Taylor Family -- Sea Level Hospital, 1964-1973 (Box 32)
  - Teer Family, 1964-1965 (Box 32)
  - Texas Company [TEXACO], 1956-1967 (Box 32)
  - Thomas, James A. Fund, 1958-1959 (Box 32)
  - Trustees Gifts, 1965-1969, [2 folders] (Box 32)
  - Union Carbide Chemicals Company, 1952-1969 (Box 32)
  - U. S. Steel Foundation, 1953-1968 (Box 32)
  - Vansant, Will -- Bequest for Cancer Research, 1965-1967 (Box 32)
  - Western Electric Company, 1956-1969 (Box 32)
  - Westinghouse Educational Foundation, 1954-1969 (Box 32)
  - Wilmington, Delaware -- Special Gifts Dinner, 1967 (Box 32)
  - Wilson, Woodrow Scholarships, 1955-1969, [2 folders] (Box 32)
  - Woodhall, Barnes -- Gifts and Grants, 1969-1970 (Box 32)
- Correspondence, 1963-1969 (Box 32)
  Alphabetically arranged, primarily by the last name of the correspondent. Contains both letters received as well as copies of letters sent from President Knight's office.
  Notable correspondents in the Correspondence Series include Les Brown; Ellen Huckabee Gobbel, a former dean in the Woman's College; and Mark Pinsky, a former editor of the Chronicle. Other correspondents include Graddon Rowlands, whose correspondence with Knight provides insights on the history of the Duke Rugby Club, and Floyd B. McKissick, a Durham attorney who represented the Duke Employees Benevolent Society.
  - Aa-An, 1963-1968 (Box 32)
  - Ao-Az, 1963-1969 (Box 32)
  - B-Be, 1963-1968 (Box 32)
  - Bi-Bv, 1964-1969, [2 folders] (Box 32)
  - Bq-Bz, 1964-1968 (Box 32)
  - C-Cl, 1963-1969 (Box 32)
  - Co-Cu [Floyd McKissick, Labor Union], 1953; 1963-1969 (Box 32)
  - D, 1963-1969 (Box 32)
  - E, 1966-1968 (Box 32)
  - E-F, 1952; 1962-1969 (Box 32)
  - G, 1963-1969 (Box 32)
  - Haa-Harrir, 1963-1969 (Box 33)
  - Harris-Heq, 1963-1969 (Box 33)
  - Her-Hz, 1964-1968 (Box 33)
  - I-J, 1963-1969 (Box 33)
  - K, 1964-1969 (Box 33)
  - L, 1963-1969 (Box 33)
  - M, 1964-1969 (Box 33)
  - N, 1963-1968 (Box 33)
  - O, 1963-1969 (Box 33)
  - Pa-Ph, 1963-1969 (Box 33)
  - Pi-Pu, 1963-1969 (Box 33)
  - Q, 1965-1967 (Box 33)
  - R [G. Rowlands, Duke Rugby Club], 1963-1969 (Box 33)
  - Sa-Sl, 1963-1968 (Box 33)
  - Sm-Sw, 1963-1969 (Box 33)
  - T, 1963-1969 (Box 33)
  - V, 1964-1969 (Box 33)
  - W, 1963-1969 (Box 33)
  - X, 1964 (Box 33)
  - Y, 1963-1969 (Box 33)
  - Z, 1964-1967 (Box 33)
- Reports, 1951-1969 (Box 33)
  Alphabetically arranged by school, department, or office. Primarily annual reports submitted to the President's Office. The Reports Series is a useful source of institutional data.
  - AAUP (Box 34)
  - Administrative Structure, 1968 (Box 34)
  - Admissions, 1960-1961; 1966-1967 (Box 34)
  - Alumni Affairs, 1959-1966, [7 folders] (Box 34)
  - Appointments Office, 1960-1968, [2 folders] (Box 34)
  - Bands, 1960-1963 (Box 34)
  - Bureau of Testing and Guidance, 1960-1964 (Box 34)
  - Business Office -- Financial Reports, 1963-1966 (Box 34)
  - Choral Music, 1960-1962 (Box 34)
  - Commonwealth Studies Center, 1956-1965 (Box 34)
  - Counseling Center, 1965-1968 (Box 34)
  - Daedalus Program -- Annual Reports, 1963 (Box 34)
  - Dean of Arts and Sciences, 1960-1967 (Box 34)
  - Dean of Men, 1958-1964, [4 folders] (Box 34)
  - Debate Activities, 1960-1963 (Box 34)
  - Dining Halls, 1960-1963 (Box 34)
  - Divinity School, 1960-1968 (Box 34)
  - Duke Players, 1960-1963 (Box 34)
  - Duke Press, 1960-1968 (Box 34)
  - Duke University -- Organization and Management, July 1960, [2 folders] (Box 34)
  - Engineering, College of, 1960-1968 (Box 34)
  - Financial Aid Office (Box 34)
    - 1951-1964 (Box 34)
    - 1960-1963 (Box 35)
  - Forestry, School of, 1960-1968 (Box 35)
  - Graduate School, 1960-1968 (Box 35)
  - Honors-Master Program, 1961-1964 (Box 35)
  - Information Services, Office of, 1959-1967 (Box 35)
  - Institutional Advancement Office, 1961-1962 (Box 35)
  - International Student Advisor, 1962-1963 (Box 35)
  - International Studies, 1966-1967 (Box 35)
  - Library, 1959-1965 (Box 35)
  - Law School, 1960-1968, [2 folders] (Box 35)
  - Library, 1966-1968 (Box 35)